Good to be with you.
I'm Tony Dokoupil.
The breaking news right now.
Banning the press.
I don't have to let them into the people's house.
TONY DOKOUPIL: THE president kicking three news organizations out of the White House.
What they're saying tonight.
And can he do this?
Air emergency.
The burned out cabin where a battery pack burst into flames hours into an overseas flight.
What to know about the danger as more passengers bring devices onto planes.
CBS News exclusive Patrick Clancy and what he wants the world to know following the killing of his three children.
I live with the outcome.
I live with it every day.
TONY DOKOUPIL: Our conversation with the 60 Minutes correspondent who got the interview as the lone holdout juror in Lindsay Clancy's murder trial breaks his silence.
What he is now saying about his vote.
Plus, the first interview with Princess Diana's brother after his accusations against the royal family.
What he said about King Charles and Prince Harry.
A mountain lion on the loose roaming the streets of San Francisco.
What happened next?
Hero dog.
The celebration for a police canine recovering after an on the job injury.
And tonight, Steve Hartman shows us when you're a parent, the days may be long, but the years are short.
STEVE HARTMAN: Why is it so hard then?
You reduce in size in their rear view mirror, but they stay the same for you.
ANNOUNCER: From CBS News headquarters in New York.
This is the CBS Evening News with Tony Dokoupil.
And good evening.
President Trump today claimed he is banning a trio of major media companies from the White House, continuing a long, hostile relationship with the press.
But while he claimed on social media that the ban on CNN, MSNOW, and Politico was effective immediately, there was no immediate follow through aside from a new round of the same old name calling inside the White House.
And as with past attempts to block coverage, he may lose this one in court.
We get the latest now from our Weijia Jiang at the White House.
WEIJIA JIANG: Tonight President Trump is defending his decision to ban CNN, Politico, and MSNOW from the White House.
A very simple ban.
I don't want them in my office.
I don't want them here.
I would say the ban would go as far as you can.
WEIJIA JIANG: Trump first made the announcement on social media, claiming the outlet shouldn't be able to constantly write or report fiction and lies when they are covering the President of the United States.
They purposely write negative news, and they do that because they want to try and diminish the Republicans in a Republican administration.
And honestly, we've done a fantastic job.
WEIJIA JIANG: Trump has a history of attacking the press.
Fake news doesn't report those stories.
Boy, that's a lot of fake news.
WEIJIA JIANG: And female reporters in particular.
You're a loud, boisterous person.
You're fake news.
Be quiet.
That's enough.
Put down the mic.
WEIJIA JIANG: He's also tried to restrict the media before.
In his first term, he revoked Jim Acosta's White House credential and barred Kaitlan Collins from an event.
Both were reporters for CNN.
Last year, he kicked the Associated Press out of the Oval Office events because the outlet refused to use Trump's chosen name, "the Gulf of America."
This ban will likely be challenged in court.
I think every time the president explains why he thinks this ban is necessary, it's actually worse for his legal case because he keeps talking about negative coverage and unfair coverage.
And again, that's what the First Amendment protects against.
In fact, in all those previous cases, access was restored to members of the press after legal battles.
This evening, reporters from all three of the outlets Trump just threatened are here at the White House doing their jobs.
And tell us they have not been asked to leave.
Tony.
Weijia, you know this train well.
You were president of the White House Correspondents' Association.
You understand the relationship between this White House and the press corps.
What do you make of it all?
That's right.
Tony, the Association is used to plenty of tension as we advocate for access.
But while Trump has gone after reporters before, this is different because he may ban entire outlets from White House grounds.
That's an escalation from keeping folks out of the Oval Office or off of Air Force One.
Tonight, the WHCA says in a statement that the Constitution protects the freedom of the press from government interference, and that is ultimately for the good of the American public, Tony.
Weijia, thank you very much.
Also today, President Trump announced a new deal with Greenland after threatening to take the island, citing US security concerns.
The president said the agreement granted the US "permanent control over Greenland's security and all other needs."
Denmark, which handles the island's foreign policy, said the deal will be signed next week.
A battery pack burst into flames yesterday hours into a flight from Amsterdam to Curacao, forcing the pilot, who was already out there over the ocean, to turn back toward land.
Tonight, we're getting our first look at the damage.
CBS's Tom Hanson joins me now with the pictures and a warning for flyers.
Hey there, Tony.
Good evening to you.
Well, some scary moments on a flight from Amsterdam yesterday after a power bank caught fire as the plane was over the Atlantic Ocean.
Just take a look at some of these images.
The incident charred the window shade and injured one passenger who suffered minor burns.
The flight was headed to Curacao, but, of course, diverted back to Amsterdam.
Now, lithium battery fires are a known issue and have been on the rise since 2020.
The FAA says there have been 77 incidents this year, 40 from battery packs, and just last month, firefighters had to rush on board an American flight in Dallas after reports of several passengers being burned when a laptop caught fire.
Now, earlier this year, the FAA showed CBS News the testing it's doing looking for ways to reduce the danger of these fires in the cabin.
The battery demos CBS saw burnt the cameras, and another test burnt a hole through the chair's seatback.
The FAA giving us this guidance.
If you notice that your device is overheating or getting hot to the touch, it is starting to swell or smoke, immediately call the flight attendant and they will fight that fire.
And the FAA strictly requires that anything with a lithium ion battery go in your carry on luggage.
That includes vapes and personal devices.
The FAA also telling us that a fire on a plane is the worst case scenario, Tony.
Really is.
Tom, thank you.
And in Los Angeles today, the driver who crashed into that metro bus earlier this week arrived in court on a stretcher wrapped in blankets to face second degree murder charges.
Officials say she was intoxicated and driving against traffic.
And to make things worse, a news helicopter covering the deadly accident also crashed, killing two on board and a pedestrian on the ground.
Now to a CBS News exclusive.
Our conversation with Patrick Clancy and his new wife, Dr. Rachel Dinis.
60 Minutes correspondent Ross Douthat interviewed the couple about the case against Patrick's ex-wife, Lindsay Clancy, whose trial, of course, for the killing of their three small children ended earlier this month without a verdict.
Patrick, for the first time since then, is taking questions on all of it.
ROSS DOUTHAT: Are you angry at yourself?
Do you feel like you failed in some way in this period?
Or do you feel like you did the best you could?
I think I did the best I could with what I had at the time.
And I live with the outcome.
I live with it every day, but I think I did the best I could.
And joining me now is 60 Minutes correspondent Ross Douthat.
Ross, great to have you here.
Great to be here.
What can we expect from the piece on Sunday?
I think the biggest thing is just a portrait of Patrick's life in the aftermath of this incredible tragedy, and what it's like to deal with that kind of grief, that kind of unimaginable experience as a father, and then what it means to try and rebuild your life in the shadow of that experience and try and go forward from there.
Why do you think Patrick Clancy wanted to do this interview?
I think from the beginning, he's been focused on trying to make sure that the memory of his children stays alive and stays close to the center of this story.
And obviously, there's been so many debates, so much controversy about all of the different issues around this story.
Mental health, marriage, men and women, the medical system, all of these things.
And there have been all kinds of, obviously, online accusations against Patrick himself.
And he felt his kids, Cora, Dawson, and Callan, were getting lost in all that noise and he wanted to put the spotlight back on them.
And so it is.
Ross, thank you very much.
Thank you.
We'll have Ross Douthat's full exclusive report on 60 Minutes this Sunday.
And tonight we're also hearing from the lone holdout juror in the Lindsay Clancy murder case.
The defense had argued that Clancy lost all control suffering from postpartum psychosis when she killed her three children.
The juror, however, says she knew exactly what she was doing.
Our Shanelle Kaul reports.
SHANELLE KAUL: The holdout juror in the Lindsay Clancy murder trial has broken his silence.
In a statement obtained by CBS News through his representative, Michael Desronvil says, I didn't have any doubts.
As I tried to explain different possible theories during deliberation, I kept getting cut off as if I had doubts based on the evidence present.
Based on all the physical evidence, key witnesses, and what the prosecution presents, I thought it was enough proof that she knew exactly what she was doing and planned.
He had said he had doubt.
SHANELLE KAUL: Paula Devlin says she was one of the 11 jurors who wanted Lindsay Clancy to be found not criminally responsible, and told us she believes the holdout juror wasn't following the law when it came to reasonable doubt.
If he had shown us some evidence, then we all would have been OK with that.
But you don't feel like that's what happened here?
Unfortunately, no.
Whose word matters more here?
The holdout juror or the 11 jurors.
The holdout juror.
100%.
Otherwise, we could have a chilling effect on the process of jury deliberations.
The holding out really is a testament to what the jury deliberation process should look like.
After the mistrial Desronvil was targeted online.
He hired a defamation lawyer, and the state, meantime, has not yet announced if it will retry Lindsay Clancy.
Tony.
Shanelle, thank you very much.
And as we've been reporting, some of the most powerful people in the AI industry are filled with worry, even dread over what might go wrong.
But NVIDIA founder and CEO Jensen Huang is not one of those people.
He sat down with our Jo Ling Kent for an exclusive interview, arguing that now is not the time to slow down.
So should we slow down, and would that affect the race with China?
We should go as fast as we can, irrespective of anybody else.
We're going to go as fast as we can, but we would never, ever and never should ship products before they're ready, deliver products that are unsafe, and nobody's expecting us to do that.
But everybody's expecting us to succeed and help America be as prosperous as possible.
You can see more of Jo Ling Kent's exclusive report with NVIDIA CEO this weekend on CBS Sunday Morning.
Still ahead on the broadcast tonight, a mountain lion on the loose and a quite literally wild chase on the streets of San Francisco.
Just two blocks North of the San Francisco Zoo, a mountain lion from the wild this morning terrorized the neighborhood.
Carter Evans now with details.
CARTER EVANS: It's a wild police chase with a fugitive feline on the streets of San Francisco.
MAN: Coming our way.
JENSEN HUANG: But this mountain lion appears to have a problem with authority ignoring police containment lines.
I thought they were exaggerating when they said we needed to get out of the way before.
But they were right.
[LAUGHS] It was just so fast.
MAN: It's beautiful.
CARTER EVANS: The animal was spotted this morning in a residential neighborhood and quickly became a media sensation.
REPORTER: Breaking news out of San Francisco, where a mountain lion has been spotted hiding under a bush.
CARTER EVANS: He's not lying.
There it is.
A terrifying sight for neighbors.
My primal instincts kicked in and I ran.
CARTER EVANS: Even the mayor took to social media.
So just avoid the area, and we will keep you posted.
CARTER EVANS: The chase finally ended with an unplanned cat nap.
Wildlife officers tranquilized the mountain lion and carried it to safety.
MAN: There it is, guys.
CARTER EVANS: The cougar culprit in custody.
Now, you may have noticed authorities with their arms up, almost as if they were trying to catch the mountain lion.
And it may look absurd, but that's exactly what wildlife experts say you should do.
Hold up your arms, look big, and definitely do not turn and run, because that could trigger the lion's instinct to chase.
Tony.
Carter, thank you very much.
When a police officer arrived at a major fire in Eau Claire, Wisconsin, early Sunday and heard that a young family was still inside.
He did not go looking for a firefighter.
He went right in himself, warned the family, and even scooped up a baby to help everyone get out and with no injuries.
Big cheers today for a police canine in Utah just released from the vet.
This is Bruno, who broke both legs on the job investigating a suspicious package with the Park City Police Department.
But he is now on the mend and reunited with his family.
Up next on the road with Steve Hartman confronts the question that every parent eventually faces.
Where did all the time go?
Finally tonight on the road where for a change, Steve Hartman stays home and for a reason every parent can relate to.
STEVE HARTMAN: It happened to my wife, Andrea, and me after our first child was born, and it happened constantly.
Do you remember the advice that pretty much everybody gave us when we first had George?
Oh my gosh, it goes so fast.
STEVE HARTMAN: Cherish this.
It goes so fast.
Yeah.
And I could not imagine it going fast.
No, and now it feels like a blink of an eye.
STEVE HARTMAN: For us, that 18 year blink just happened.
George is starting college, and although we have taught him everything he needs to know to live independently, except maybe how to pack a t-shirt.
I suppose I'll figure that out.
STEVE HARTMAN: No one ever taught us how to deal with his vacancy.
How to get past this most puzzling parenting paradox.
He annoys us sometimes now.
Yeah, I think all children do.
We annoy him.
We annoy him immensely.
[LAUGHS] Yeah.
Why is it so hard then?
You send your kids off to college, and you reduce in size in their rear view mirror.
STEVE HARTMAN: Yeah.
But they stay the same for you.
As parents, I think you just imagine your kids are always going to be there until one night there's an empty spot at the dinner table.
STEVE HARTMAN: In preparation for that moment, every couple of years I interviewed my kids, hoping to capture that time as it flew by.
From those early days of steely confidence.
What do you want to be when you grow up?
Chemist or an astrophysicist.
STEVE HARTMAN: Through the tender times of his first crush.
What makes her special?
Her liking me back, honestly, is what makes that really special.
STEVE HARTMAN: I even have those memorable years that hardly seem worth remembering.
They say that sometimes when kids hit puberty, they get moody.
Whatever.
STEVE HARTMAN: I have saved it all.
Unfortunately, documenting the passage of time doesn't change our perception of it.
No matter how many photos you take or videos you record, it's still over in an instant.
George left for school earlier this month.
He'll major in math.
And as for us remainders, I'm doing OK.
But my wife-- well, it's going to take her a little longer to adjust.
And not only because she misses him.
How much of it do you think is you're just worried about having to spend more time with me?
Big part.
STEVE HARTMAN: Steve Hartman from an "emptier nest" in New York.
Steve Hartman on what he calls "the 18-year blink."
Thank you, Steve.
That's another day in America.
I'm Tony Dokoupil.
For all of us here at CBS News, thank you for watching this week.
We'll see you right back here on Monday.
Good night.